Finding Aid for the Roderic Gorney papers, 1974-1980
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 3. Research Study
  - PSAF Program Materials, program notebook (2 of 2), 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Attitudes, notes, April 1976 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Values, notes, April 1976 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Values Tables and Figures, April 1976 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Values - raw transfer, undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Behavior Tables and Figures, April 1976 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Behavior - DL edit, LL, ISSR, undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Behavior Notes, April 1976 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Situational (Demographic) Effects notes, April, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Demography notes, October 1975 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Frequency Distribution notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Master list of tables and figures, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cross-modal Tables and Figures, guidelines, April 1976 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Cross-modal notes, April 1976 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Cross-modal Personality/Attitudes/Values notes, March 18, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - D Group Analysis, February 1976 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Fantasy new analysis, February 1976 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Completion, Other table and figure needs, April 1976 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - CCR guidelines, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Markle: Morrisett Proposal, October 1975 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Key Papers: J. B-R "A Dependency Model of Mass Media Effects", January 1976 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Stimulus: +, - Rating study, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - First Results for the Study Mass Entertainment and Human Survival, A Report to the Lilly Endowment, Inc., February 23, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mood Adjective notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Mood Integrative Notes, October 1975 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Mood - Ideation Integrative notes, October 1975 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Ideation Integration notes, October 1975 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Rater reliability checks, fantasy scores notes, January 12, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - 1st Fantasy Analysis: Raw, Husbands' data and notes, October 10, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - 1st Fantasy Analysis: Raw, Wives' data and notes, October 10, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Codebook for data on marital happiness, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Punch Cards: Assessment of Husband by Wife, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Punch Cards: item scores, pre/post, 1974 (Box 21)
  - Computer data, analysis of variance and covariance, 1974 (Box 22)
  - PSAF computer printouts, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Punch cards, 1974 (Box 24)
  - PSAF computer printouts, 1974 (Box 25)
  - PSAF computer printouts, 1974 (Box 26)
  - Video tapes (Beta), Vol. 1-7, 13-14, 1974 (Box 27)
  - Video tapes (Beta), Vol. 15-22, 39-40, 1974 (Box 28)
  - Video tapes (Beta), Vol. 23, 31-38, 41, 1974 (Box 29)
  - Steele Gorney Training, Husband's inkblot sheets, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Values notes, October 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Value change scores, raw data transfer, March 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Personality analysis notes, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Personality - DL edit, LL, ISSK, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Tables, change scores for personality, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Personality, raw transfer, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - VIP Personality x behavior x mood analysis notes, October 1975 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Treatment x behavior x personality, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - PSAF Television Study: A Summary of Results, notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Personality tables figures, guidelines, April 1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Fantasy notes, October 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Personality notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Secondary personality x behavior notes, Spring and Fall 1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Personality notes, April 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Findings notes, October 1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Methodology: cable, husband wife, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Variables and measures: early summary, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Theory, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1st Regression analysis behavior x mood x personality, October 1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Secondary behavior analysis, notes, Spring 1975 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Basic analysis outline, December 20, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Instructions for Barron, October 31, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Staff meeting notes, March, April 1976 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - D Group, January, February (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Rater reliability follow through, April 1976 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Work documents, data analysis meeting, December 15, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Hypothesis for analysis, January 13, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Data analysis notes, December 1975 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Data analysis memo, November 27, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Outline for hypothesis, December 1975 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Randomization and matching of sample, notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - New Instructions, etc., undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gary's backgrounders, December 1975 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Nielson National TV Ratings, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - DMUQ transfer sheets, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - DMUQ transfer sheets, Steel copy, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Table/figure production: Demographic, May 1976 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - DMUQ Items 037-046: Work with correlations, etc., November 1975 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - DMUQ correlational work (items 001-036), 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - DMUQ proposed codes, October, November 1975 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Technical reports, GS contribution, August 1975 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - TV and movie coding, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Values article notes, October 1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - PSAF/National comparisons, February 1976 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - D Group, notes on work, June 1976 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - D Group behavior transfer sheets, February 1976 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Loye/Gorney/Steele: "Effects on Adults of Prosocial vs. Violent Television Drama" copy of manuscript, April 1976 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Rater reliability, August 1976 and later, August 13-16, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - "Backlash" hypothesis notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - "Matching" procedure, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Hypothesis, December 1975 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Loye/Gorney/Steele: "Effects on Adults of Prosocial vs. Violent Television Drama" materials, table headings, etc., undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Loye -- APA Paper; MEHS: TV potential for prosocial, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Sandra clusters value change, change score analysis, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Loye -- Manuscript Follow-up correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Loye -- Chronological letter file, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Loye -- publishing letters, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Copies of manuscripts, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Nowlis, Vincent "Research with the Mood Adjective Check List", 1965 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Cross Cultural File, lists of journals and articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Amhara (MP5), undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Andamans (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Andamans (AZ2), undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Apayao (OA5), undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Binomial test notes: Treated vs. untreated group difference, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Araucanians, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Austrians (EK1), undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Aweikoma, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Azande (FO7), undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Burmese (AP4), undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Callinago (ST13), undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Chagga (FN4), undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Cheyenne (NQ8), undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Chukee (RY2), undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Attitude notes, October 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Value charts for analysis, analysis notes, November 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Video tapes (Beta), Vol. 42-51, 1974 (Box 30)
  - Video tapes (Beta), Vol. 66-75, 1974 (Box 31)
  - Video tapes (Beta), Vol. 24-30, 60, 64, 65, 1974 (Box 32)
  - Video tapes (Beta), Vol. 53-59, 61-62; Chapters 8-12, 3 (includes Super 8 film), 1974 (Box 33)
  - Video tapes (Beta), Vol. 76-82, 8-11, 1974 (Box 34)
  - PSAF computer printouts, reference materials, 1974 (Box 35)
  - Punch cards, including program deck for validity of AVS (sexism scale), ISSR printouts and guide to ISSR codes, and 1 folder of reference articles, 1974-1976 (Box 36)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Copper Eskimo (ND8), undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Ifaluk (Woleaians), undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Ila (FQ6), undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Iraqi (MH1), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Irish (ER1), undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Iroquois (NM9), undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Italians (EI11), undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Kababish (MQ9), undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Kafirs (AV6), undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Kapauku (OJ29), undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Kazaks, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Coyotero (Western Apache), undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Klallam (NR15), undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Koreans (AA1), undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Land Dyaks (OC8), undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Luo, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Malaita (ON9), undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Malekula (OO12), undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Mangareva (OX5), undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Mataco (S17), undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Mende (FC7), undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Mongo (FO32), undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Dutch (EF-1), undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Mosquito (SA15), undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Nahua (Aztecs; NU7), undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Ojibwa (NG6), undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Ona (SH4), undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Orokaiva (OJ23), undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Papago (NU28), undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Semang (AN7), undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Southern Paiute (NT16), undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Tallensi (FE11), undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Thonga (FT6), undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Egyptians (MR1, MR13), undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Tikopia (OT11), undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Tiv (FF57), undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Tongan (DU9), undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Toradja (OG11), undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Turkey (MB1), undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Yagua, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Wintun, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Human relations area file, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Progress Reports, February 10, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Notes, tables regarding findings, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Eyak (NA7), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Data analysis, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Expert raters, September 1974 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Aggression, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Competition, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Interpersonal Intensity, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Mental Illness, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Synergy, July and August 1974 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- FUR (MQ8), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Gilyak (RX2), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Gonds (AW32), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Hottentot (FX13), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fantasy scoring procedures, results -- Restricted, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - TV Study, participant information and test checklists and data [Subject names withheld] -- Restricted, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Theta cable file and correspondence regarding programs to watch during study -- Restricted, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Correspondence regarding PSAF programming and procedures -- Restricted, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 232)
    Includes one participant questionnaire response.
  - Program notebook: Programs to watch, draft letters to participants, daily schedules and instructions, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - Program notebook: blank surveys, appendices, blank rating forms, draft correspondence -- Restricted, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - Essay submissions on TV effects for cash prizes [Participant names withheld] -- Restricted, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Procedure Memo: First mailing -- Restricted, undated (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Procedure Memo: Second mailing -- Restricted, undated (Box 5, Folder 237)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- checklist original forms [Participant names withheld] -- Restricted, undated (Box 5, Folder 238)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Letters to judges -- Restricted, May 1975 (Box 5, Folder 239)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judges list [Participant names withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 240)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge rejection forms [Participant names withheld] -- Restricted, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 241)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge letter [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, July 1975 (Box 5, Folder 242)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge letter [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, June - September 1975 (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire Responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire Responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - Participant remuneration [Participant names withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Essay winners [Participant names withheld] -- Restricted, April 23, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Informed Consent forms [Participant names withheld] -- Restricted, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5-230)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Loye-Gorney-Steele "Effects on Adults of Prosocial vs. Violent Television Drama" original manuscript -- Restricted, January 11, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Loye, David "A Review of Research Bearing on the Impact of Television and Motion Pictures on Children and Adults" Appendix A -- Restricted, June 1974 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Journal submission "Impact on Adults of Dramatized Television Programs" -- Restricted, September 2, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Draft notes for "Impact on Adults of Dramatized Television Programs" -- Restricted, June 1976 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Attitudes of women, blank form -- Restricted, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - W.A. Group 1, Participants 101 to 114 -- Restricted, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - W.A. Group 2, Participants 201 to 255 -- Restricted, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - W.A. Group 3, Participants 301 to 314 -- Restricted, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - W.A. Group 4, Participants 401 to 447 -- Restricted, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Women's Behavior Survey score info data -- Restricted, November 1975 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Barron Data - Raw data transfer sheets -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - DMUQ: Husbands (questionnaire responses) -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - DMUQ: Wives (questionnaire responses) -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - The PSAF Opinion Survey Participants 02001 to 02071 -- Restricted, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 23 to 93)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - PSAF Cross Cultural Study -- Judge questionnaire responses [Participant name withheld] -- Restricted, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Loye-Gorney-Steele "Effects on Adults of Prosocial vs. Violent Television Drama" drafts -- Restricted, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Loye-Gorney-Steele "Effects on Adults of Prosocial vs. Violent Television Drama" notes -- Restricted, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The PSAF Opinion Survey Participants 02072 to 02300 -- Restricted, 1974 (Box 7)
  - PSAF Questionnaires and inkblot responses, wives and husbands #s 01101 - 01123 -- Restricted, September and October 1974 (Box 8)
  - PSAF Questionnaires and inkblot responses, wives and husbands #s 01124 - 01146 -- Restricted, September and October 1974 (Box 9)